export const chapter3StudyData = [
  // Key Terms
  {
    id: "KT301",
    front: "action potential",
    back: "electrical signal that moves down the neuron's axon"
  },
  {
    id: "KT302",
    front: "adrenal gland",
    back: "sits atop our kidneys and secretes hormones involved in the stress response"
  },
  {
    id: "KT303",
    front: "agonist",
    back: "drug that mimics or strengthens the effects of a neurotransmitter"
  },
  {
    id: "KT304",
    front: "all-or-none",
    back: "phenomenon that incoming signal from another neuron is either sufficient or insufficient to reach the threshold of excitation"
  },
  {
    id: "KT305",
    front: "allele",
    back: "specific version of a gene"
  },
  {
    id: "KT306",
    front: "amygdala",
    back: "structure in the limbic system involved in our experience of emotion and tying emotional meaning to our memories"
  },
  {
    id: "KT307",
    front: "antagonist",
    back: "drug that blocks or impedes the normal activity of a given neurotransmitter"
  },
  {
    id: "KT308",
    front: "auditory cortex",
    back: "strip of cortex in the temporal lobe that is responsible for processing auditory information"
  },
  {
    id: "KT309",
    front: "autonomic nervous system",
    back: "controls our internal organs and glands"
  },
  {
    id: "KT310",
    front: "axon",
    back: "major extension of the soma"
  },
  {
    id: "KT311",
    front: "biological perspective",
    back: "view that psychological disorders like depression and schizophrenia are associated with imbalances in one or more neurotransmitter systems"
  },
  {
    id: "KT312",
    front: "Broca's area",
    back: "region in the left hemisphere that is essential for language production"
  },
  {
    id: "KT313",
    front: "central nervous system (CNS)",
    back: "brain and spinal cord"
  },
  {
    id: "KT314",
    front: "cerebellum",
    back: "hindbrain structure that controls our balance, coordination, movement, and motor skills, and it is thought to be important in processing some types of memory"
  },
  {
    id: "KT315",
    front: "cerebral cortex",
    back: "surface of the brain that is associated with our highest mental capabilities"
  },
  {
    id: "KT316",
    front: "chromosome",
    back: "long strand of genetic information"
  },
  {
    id: "KT317",
    front: "computerized tomography (CT) scan",
    back: "imaging technique in which a computer coordinates and integrates multiple x-rays of a given area"
  },
  {
    id: "KT318",
    front: "corpus callosum",
    back: "thick band of neural fibers connecting the brain's two hemispheres"
  },
  {
    id: "KT319",
    front: "dendrite",
    back: "branch-like extension of the soma that receives incoming signals from other neurons"
  },
  {
    id: "KT320",
    front: "deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA)",
    back: "helix-shaped molecule made of nucleotide base pairs"
  },
  {
    id: "KT321",
    front: "diabetes",
    back: "disease related to insufficient insulin production"
  },
  {
    id: "KT322",
    front: "dominant allele",
    back: "allele whose phenotype will be expressed in an individual that possesses that allele"
  },
  {
    id: "KT323",
    front: "electroencephalography (EEG)",
    back: "recording the electrical activity of the brain via electrodes on the scalp"
  },
  {
    id: "KT324",
    front: "endocrine system",
    back: "series of glands that produce chemical substances known as hormones"
  },
  {
    id: "KT325",
    front: "epigenetics",
    back: "study of gene-environment interactions, such as how the same genotype leads to different phenotypes"
  },
  {
    id: "KT326",
    front: "fight or flight response",
    back: "activation of the sympathetic division of the autonomic nervous system, allowing access to energy reserves and heightened sensory capacity so that we might fight off a given threat or run away to safety"
  },
  {
    id: "KT327",
    front: "forebrain",
    back: "largest part of the brain, containing the cerebral cortex, the thalamus, and the limbic system, among other structures"
  },
  {
    id: "KT328",
    front: "fraternal twins",
    back: "twins who develop from two different eggs fertilized by different sperm, so their genetic material varies the same as in non-twin siblings"
  },
  {
    id: "KT329",
    front: "frontal lobe",
    back: "part of the cerebral cortex involved in reasoning, motor control, emotion, and language; contains motor cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT330",
    front: "functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI)",
    back: "MRI that shows changes in metabolic activity over time"
  },
  {
    id: "KT331",
    front: "gene",
    back: "sequence of DNA that controls or partially controls physical characteristics"
  },
  {
    id: "KT332",
    front: "genetic environmental correlation",
    back: "view of gene-environment interaction that asserts our genes affect our environment, and our environment influences the expression of our genes"
  },
  {
    id: "KT333",
    front: "genotype",
    back: "genetic makeup of an individual"
  },
  {
    id: "KT334",
    front: "glial cell",
    back: "nervous system cell that provides physical and metabolic support to neurons, including neuronal insulation and communication, and nutrient and waste transport"
  },
  {
    id: "KT335",
    front: "gonad",
    back: "secretes sexual hormones, which are important for successful reproduction, and mediate both sexual motivation and behavior"
  },
  {
    id: "KT336",
    front: "gyrus (plural: gyri)",
    back: "bump or ridge on the cerebral cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT337",
    front: "hemisphere",
    back: "left or right half of the brain"
  },
  {
    id: "KT338",
    front: "heterozygous",
    back: "consisting of two different alleles"
  },
  {
    id: "KT339",
    front: "hindbrain",
    back: "division of the brain containing the medulla, pons, and cerebellum"
  },
  {
    id: "KT340",
    front: "hippocampus",
    back: "structure in the temporal lobe associated with learning and memory"
  },
  {
    id: "KT341",
    front: "homeostasis",
    back: "state of equilibrium-biological conditions, such as body temperature, are maintained at optimal levels"
  },
  {
    id: "KT342",
    front: "homozygous",
    back: "consisting of two identical alleles"
  },
  {
    id: "KT343",
    front: "hormone",
    back: "chemical messenger released by endocrine glands"
  },
  {
    id: "KT344",
    front: "hypothalamus",
    back: "forebrain structure that regulates sexual motivation and behavior and a number of homeostatic processes; serves as an interface between the nervous system and the endocrine system"
  },
  {
    id: "KT345",
    front: "identical twins",
    back: "twins that develop from the same sperm and egg"
  },
  {
    id: "KT346",
    front: "lateralization",
    back: "concept that each hemisphere of the brain is associated with specialized functions"
  },
  {
    id: "KT347",
    front: "limbic system",
    back: "collection of structures involved in processing emotion and memory"
  },
  {
    id: "KT348",
    front: "longitudinal fissure",
    back: "deep groove in the brain's cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT349",
    front: "magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)",
    back: "magnetic fields used to produce a picture of the tissue being imaged"
  },
  {
    id: "KT350",
    front: "medulla",
    back: "hindbrain structure that controls automated processes like breathing, blood pressure, and heart rate"
  },
  {
    id: "KT351",
    front: "membrane potential",
    back: "difference in charge across the neuronal membrane"
  },
  {
    id: "KT352",
    front: "midbrain",
    back: "division of the brain located between the forebrain and the hindbrain; contains the reticular formation"
  },
  {
    id: "KT353",
    front: "motor cortex",
    back: "strip of cortex involved in planning and coordinating movement"
  },
  {
    id: "KT354",
    front: "mutation",
    back: "sudden, permanent change in a gene"
  },
  {
    id: "KT355",
    front: "myelin sheath",
    back: "fatty substance that insulates axons"
  },
  {
    id: "KT356",
    front: "neuron",
    back: "cells in the nervous system that act as interconnected information processors, which are essential for all of the tasks of the nervous system"
  },
  {
    id: "KT357",
    front: "neurotransmitter",
    back: "chemical messenger of the nervous system"
  },
  {
    id: "KT358",
    front: "occipital lobe",
    back: "part of the cerebral cortex associated with visual processing; contains the primary visual cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT359",
    front: "pancreas",
    back: "secretes hormones that regulate blood sugar"
  },
  {
    id: "KT360",
    front: "parasympathetic nervous system",
    back: "associated with routine, day-to-day operations of the body"
  },
  {
    id: "KT361",
    front: "parietal lobe",
    back: "part of the cerebral cortex involved in processing various sensory and perceptual information; contains the primary somatosensory cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT362",
    front: "peripheral nervous system (PNS)",
    back: "connects the brain and spinal cord to the muscles, organs and senses in the periphery of the body"
  },
  {
    id: "KT363",
    front: "phenotype",
    back: "individual's inheritable physical characteristics"
  },
  {
    id: "KT364",
    front: "pituitary gland",
    back: "secretes a number of key hormones, which regulate fluid levels in the body, and a number of messenger hormones, which direct the activity of other glands in the endocrine system"
  },
  {
    id: "KT365",
    front: "polygenic",
    back: "multiple genes affecting a given trait"
  },
  {
    id: "KT366",
    front: "pons",
    back: "hindbrain structure that connects the brain and spinal cord; involved in regulating brain activity during sleep"
  },
  {
    id: "KT367",
    front: "positron emission tomography (PET) scan",
    back: "involves injecting individuals with a mildly radioactive substance and monitoring changes in blood flow to different regions of the brain"
  },
  {
    id: "KT368",
    front: "prefrontal cortex",
    back: "area in the frontal lobe responsible for higher-level cognitive functioning"
  },
  {
    id: "KT369",
    front: "psychotropic medication",
    back: "drugs that treat psychiatric symptoms by restoring neurotransmitter balance"
  },
  {
    id: "KT370",
    front: "range of reaction",
    back: "asserts our genes set the boundaries within which we can operate, and our environment interacts with the genes to determine where in that range we will fall"
  },
  {
    id: "KT371",
    front: "receptor",
    back: "protein on the cell surface where neurotransmitters attach"
  },
  {
    id: "KT372",
    front: "recessive allele",
    back: "allele whose phenotype will be expressed only if an individual is homozygous for that allele"
  },
  {
    id: "KT373",
    front: "resting potential",
    back: "the state of readiness of a neuron membrane's potential between signals"
  },
  {
    id: "KT374",
    front: "reticular formation",
    back: "midbrain structure important in regulating the sleep/wake cycle, arousal, alertness, and motor activity"
  },
  {
    id: "KT375",
    front: "reuptake",
    back: "neurotransmitter is pumped back into the neuron that released it"
  },
  {
    id: "KT376",
    front: "semipermeable membrane",
    back: "cell membrane that allows smaller molecules or molecules without an electrical charge to pass through it, while stopping larger or highly charged molecules"
  },
  {
    id: "KT377",
    front: "soma",
    back: "cell body"
  },
  {
    id: "KT378",
    front: "somatic nervous system",
    back: "relays sensory and motor information to and from the CNS"
  },
  {
    id: "KT379",
    front: "somatosensory cortex",
    back: "essential for processing sensory information from across the body, such as touch, temperature, and pain"
  },
  {
    id: "KT380",
    front: "substantia nigra",
    back: "midbrain structure where dopamine is produced; involved in control of movement"
  },
  {
    id: "KT381",
    front: "sulcus (plural: sulci)",
    back: "depressions or grooves in the cerebral cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT382",
    front: "sympathetic nervous system",
    back: "involved in stress-related activities and functions"
  },
  {
    id: "KT383",
    front: "synapse",
    back: "small gap between two neurons where communication occurs"
  },
  {
    id: "KT384",
    front: "synaptic vesicle",
    back: "storage site for neurotransmitters"
  },
  {
    id: "KT385",
    front: "temporal lobe",
    back: "part of cerebral cortex associated with hearing, memory, emotion, and some aspects of language; contains primary auditory cortex"
  },
  {
    id: "KT386",
    front: "terminal button",
    back: "axon terminal containing synaptic vesicles"
  },
  {
    id: "KT387",
    front: "thalamus",
    back: "sensory relay for the brain"
  },
  {
    id: "KT388",
    front: "theory of evolution by natural selection",
    back: "states that organisms that are better suited for their environments will survive and reproduce compared to those that are poorly suited for their environments"
  },
  {
    id: "KT389",
    front: "threshold of excitation",
    back: "level of charge in the membrane that causes the neuron to become active"
  },
  {
    id: "KT390",
    front: "thyroid",
    back: "secretes hormones that regulate growth, metabolism, and appetite"
  },
  {
    id: "KT391",
    front: "ventral tegmental area (VTA)",
    back: "midbrain structure where dopamine is produced: associated with mood, reward, and addiction"
  },
  {
    id: "KT392",
    front: "Wernicke's area",
    back: "important for speech comprehension"
  },
  // Review Questions
  {
    id: "R301",
    front: "A(n) ________ is a sudden, permanent change in a sequence of DNA.",
    back: "mutation"
  },
  {
    id: "R302",
    front: "________ refers to a person's genetic makeup, while ________ refers to a person's physical characteristics.",
    back: "Genotype; phenotype"
  },
  {
    id: "R303",
    front: "________ is the field of study that focuses on genes and their expression.",
    back: "Epigenetics"
  },
  {
    id: "R304",
    front: "Humans have ________ pairs of chromosomes.",
    back: "23"
  },
  {
    id: "R305",
    front: "The ________ receive(s) incoming signals from other neurons.",
    back: "dendrites"
  },
  {
    id: "R306",
    front: "A(n) ________ facilitates or mimics the activity of a given neurotransmitter system.",
    back: "agonist"
  },
  {
    id: "R307",
    front: "Multiple sclerosis involves a breakdown of the ________.",
    back: "myelin sheath"
  },
  {
    id: "R308",
    front: "An action potential involves Na+ moving ________ the cell and K+ moving ________ the cell.",
    back: "inside; outside"
  },
  {
    id: "R309",
    front: "Our ability to make our legs move as we walk across the room is controlled by the ________ nervous system.",
    back: "somatic"
  },
  {
    id: "R310",
    front: "If your ________ is activated, you will feel relatively at ease.",
    back: "parasympathetic nervous system"
  },
  {
    id: "R311",
    front: "The central nervous system is comprised of ________.",
    back: "brain and spinal cord"
  },
  {
    id: "R312",
    front: "Sympathetic activation is associated with ________.",
    back: "both A and C (pupil dilation and increased heart rate)"
  },
  {
    id: "R313",
    front: "The ________ is a sensory relay station where all sensory information, except for smell, goes before being sent to other areas of the brain for further processing.",
    back: "thalamus"
  },
  {
    id: "R314",
    front: "Damage to the ________ disrupts one's ability to comprehend language, but it leaves one's ability to produce words intact.",
    back: "Wernicke's Area"
  },
  {
    id: "R315",
    front: "A(n) ________ uses magnetic fields to create pictures of a given tissue.",
    back: "MRI"
  },
  {
    id: "R316",
    front: "Which of the following is not a structure of the forebrain?",
    back: "substantia nigra"
  },
  {
    id: "R317",
    front: "The two major hormones secreted from the pancreas are:",
    back: "glucagon and insulin"
  },
  {
    id: "R318",
    front: "The ________ secretes messenger hormones that direct the function of the rest of the endocrine glands.",
    back: "pituitary"
  },
  {
    id: "R319",
    front: "The ________ gland secretes epinephrine.",
    back: "adrenal"
  },
  {
    id: "R320",
    front: "The ________ secretes hormones that regulate the body's fluid levels.",
    back: "pituitary"
  }
];

export default chapter3StudyData;
